<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>悦子yuezi的博客</title><link>https://Yuezi-1223.github.io/yuezi.github.io</link><description>As always.</description><copyright>悦子yuezi的博客</copyright><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><image><url>https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/176132540?v=4</url><title>avatar</title><link>https://Yuezi-1223.github.io/yuezi.github.io</link></image><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 05:45:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><managingEditor>悦子yuezi的博客</managingEditor><ttl>60</ttl><webMaster>悦子yuezi的博客</webMaster><item><title>Study Note | Ethnic Divisions and Segregation, Harvard 2023</title><link>https://Yuezi-1223.github.io/yuezi.github.io/post/Study%20Note%20-%20Ethnic%20Divisions%20and%20Segregation%2C%20Harvard%202023.html</link><description>_Written &amp; Organized by 悦子yuezi_&#13;
_Issue Date: 2024/07/20_&#13;
&#13;
# Basic Definitions&#13;
## Ethnicity&#13;
- a group identity based on a belief in a **common origin**&#13;
- Ethnic groups highlight (supposed) unique cultural aspects to mark inter-group differences and hierarchy&#13;
- Often ethnic identity definition is relative to external “others”&#13;
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]&#13;
&gt; _Weber_: That belief is the foundation of identification with an ethnic group, solidarity among group members and definition of common goals.&#13;
&#13;
## Racial Division&#13;
- Social categorization based on **phenotypic** or **biological** criteria&#13;
&#13;
## Nationalism&#13;
- A group’s demand for autonomy in a territory considered to be the group’s homeland &#13;
- usually a demand for a **sovereign state**&#13;
&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
# Ethnic boundaries and culture&#13;
## Social constructivist approach to ethnicity&#13;
- Ethnicity (and race, and nationhood) is a way of viewing the world. It belongs to the real of cognition (its “existence” not ontological but **phenomenological**).&#13;
- Ethnicity (and race, and nationhood) is a **social construct**: it is created and changes through social interactions and symbolic actions.&#13;
- Ethnic boundary making often through **inter-group competition**.&#13;
- Ethnicity has serious implications for people's lives.&#13;
&#13;
## _Jekins_: What is being constructed? &#13;
- Category's boundaries&#13;
- Beliefs about the traits or cultural contents that mark differences between 'us' and them”&#13;
&#13;
## Characteristics of the ethnic boundaries&#13;
- Ethnic boundaries are **fluid**.&#13;
- Ethnic boundaries are sometimes **blurred**.&#13;
- These principles contrast with common sensical view of ethnicity (and race and nation).&#13;
&#13;
## The development of the boundaries approach to ethnicity&#13;
- **Classic cultural anthropology** → Barth → Post Barth&#13;
&gt; Classic cultural anthropology classified ethnic and racial groups based on supposed objective traits.&#13;
&gt; Classification system reflected power relations imperialism and colonialism)&#13;
&#13;
## _Barth_: Ojective definition of ethnic boundries&#13;
- **Relationality**. Ethnic groups are not developed in isolation, but through **interactions** with other groups (key observation: people cross ethnic boundaries!). &#13;
&gt; [!NOTE]&#13;
&gt; Groups are not defined by their culture, which is not an objective unique identifier (there are in-group differences and there are shared traits with out-groups) and changes over time. Ethnicity is a form of **social organization**.&#13;
- What matters is the **subjective demarcation** of boundaries between “us” and “them” by people in the field.&#13;
- Ethnic boundaries limit and prescribe social interactions.&#13;
-  Research should focus on the actions through which ethnic boundaries maintain or change.&#13;
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]&#13;
&gt; There are no objective cultural markers of groups. Instead, people on the ground decide which cultural materials matter for their collective identity.&#13;
&#13;
## Post Barth Research&#13;
- Greater emphasis on the fluidity of ethnic boundaries.&#13;
- Interest in the links between symbolic boundaries and social boundaries.&#13;
- Situational ethnicity/ethnicity as cognition&#13;
- Setting the limits to constructivism&#13;
&#13;
## Social Boundary and Symbolic Boundary&#13;
### 1. Social Boundary&#13;
- Social boundaries refer to the tangible and observable divisions that exist in the real world, separating and distinguishing different social groups. &#13;
- These divisions can be based on various factors such as geography, ethnicity, class, religion, or political affiliations. &#13;
- Social boundaries can influence the distribution of resources, power dynamics, and social interactions among individuals and groups. &#13;
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]&#13;
&gt; Social boundaries are **objective** and have a **physical** presence, often manifested in institutional structures and societal norms.&#13;
### 2. Symbolic Boundary&#13;
- Symbolic boundaries are conceptual and constructed through cultural and symbolic representations. &#13;
- They involve the ways in which individuals and groups differentiate themselves and others based on shared meanings, values, and beliefs. &#13;
- Symbolic boundaries are not necessarily tied to physical or spatial separations; instead, they are rooted in the realm of ideas, language, and cultural practices. &#13;
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]&#13;
&gt; Symbolic boundaries are **subjective** and only have an **abstract** presence, they influence perceptions of identity, belonging, and group membership.&#13;
### Relationsips between Social and Symbolic boundaries&#13;
- Symbolic boundaries can **reinforce or challenge** social boundaries&#13;
&gt; Cultural representations and symbolic markers can strengthen group cohesion and reinforce social boundaries, leading to a sense of 'us versus them.' Conversely, symbolic boundaries can also be used to challenge and contest existing social boundaries, contributing to social change and transformation.&#13;
- Social boundaries can **be legitimized** through symbolic boundaries&#13;
&gt; The way a society conceptualizes and represents different social groups, often through media, language, and cultural practices, can legitimize and perpetuate existing social boundaries, either maintaining or reproducing social inequalities.&#13;
- Social boundaries may **influence the formation** of symbolic boundaries&#13;
&gt; The material conditions and power dynamics associated with social boundaries can shape the ways in which groups construct their symbolic boundaries. For example, oppressed or marginalized groups may use symbolic resistance as a means to challenge the dominant social order.&#13;
&#13;
&gt; [!NOTE]&#13;
&gt; What is similar and what is different about the relationships of ethnicity with language and with religion?&#13;
&gt; ### Similar:&#13;
&gt; - Religion sometimes serves as a marker of ethnicity, but the two **do not fully overlap**. &#13;
&gt; - Highlighting religious differences is a political processes _(e.g., to justify claims for material, political, or symbolic resources)_&#13;
&gt; ### Difference:&#13;
&gt; - Sometimes, religion becomes a trans-ethnic or trans-national identity. &#13;
&gt; - Religions provide materials for thick ethnic (or national) identities: idioms, myths, and symbols that add moral and affective load to group membership.&#13;
&gt; - Religious organizations participate in ethnic (or national) identity **construction and socialization**.&#13;
&#13;
## Further viewpoints&#13;
- Culture marks ethnic boundaries, but it also gives content and meaning to **identities** _(“thick identity”)_.&#13;
- This does not mean that we should essentialize ethnic or national culture.&#13;
- Ethnic and national groups are sites of struggles over the meanings attached to **a collective identity** (e.g., different beliefs about the group’s history, its core values, etc., sometimes also about symbolic boundaries).&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&#13;
# Boundary Work and Shifts&#13;
## _Nagel_: What caused large-scale ethnic switching? What caused the **fluidity**?&#13;
- Federal policy&#13;
- Ethnic politics&#13;
- Political activism, shared fate, pride, and inspiration&#13;
&#13;
## Characteristics of fluid boundaries:&#13;
- **Cultural differentiation**&#13;
&gt; i.e., identifying certain cultural traits, habits, behaviors, etc. as typical for “us” or for “them”&#13;
- **Social closure**&#13;
&gt; closure and differentiation tend to reinforce each other&#13;
- **Political salience**&#13;
&gt; “thick” identities reduce the range of possible political actions; ethnic politics tends to reinforce differentiation and closure&#13;
&#13;
## Boundary work&#13;
- The phenomenon of individuals or groups **creating, maintaining, adjusting, or breaking through** various boundaries in society, such as ethnic, cultural, social, etc., **to shape identity, group relationships, and social interactions**.&#13;
- Ethnic categories may **expand or contract** (a focal topic in ethnic studies) due to boundary work.&#13;
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]&#13;
&gt; _Wimmer_: People have repertoires of identities to chose from. Their choices may change when institutional incentives change. So, **repertories ≠ situational ethnicity**.&#13;
&#13;
## Components of Boundary Work&#13;
- **Type of boundary**&#13;
&gt; which criteria for similarity/difference (e.g., ethnicity, race, gender, nationality, generation) is highlighted in the pursue or recognition and/or political power?&#13;
- **Type of strategy**&#13;
&gt; e.g., boundary crossing; normative inversion; expansion; contraction&#13;
- **Location of boundary**&#13;
&gt; membership rule: what is the criterion or threshold for being one of “us”?&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&#13;
# Pan-ethnicity, situational ethnicity, the limit of constructivism&#13;
## Situational Ethnicity&#13;
-  Individuals or groups actively choosing to emphasize or express a specific ethnic identity in a particular context. &#13;
- This identity is determined by the current social environment, social situations, or specific contexts, and may change due to different situations.&#13;
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]&#13;
&gt; Individuals or groups selectively emphasize or conceal their ethnic identity based on different social contexts to **adapt to different social needs or express a sense of belonging**. &#13;
&#13;
## Impacts of (activated) ethnic identification (self or other) on social interactions&#13;
-  Cognitive schemes of interpretation (_Brubaker：Ethnicity as Cognition_)&#13;
- Affective dispositions (sometimes _hot cognition_)&#13;
- Behavioral tendencies&#13;
- But interactions can also generate shifts in the above _(e.g., contact theory)_&#13;
&#13;
## Two types of variation in ethnic identification&#13;
- **Temporal** (i.e., the conditions that evoke different degrees and expressions of ethnic identification).&#13;
&gt; e.g., In certain specific social events or cultural celebrations, individuals may express their ethnic identity more strongly, while in other everyday contexts, ethnic identity may be relatively weak or less prominent.&#13;
- **Cross-sectional**: hierarchies of identities (i.e., identities’ relative degree of salience).&#13;
&gt; e.g., A person may emphasize their professional identity more in the workplace, while emphasizing their ethnic identity more at family gatherings.&#13;
&#13;
## Instrumental ethnicity&#13;
- Sometimes ethnicity is used instrumentally, but that is because it has been **internalized** and is considered **primordial**. &#13;
- Also, there is a difference between superficial act of signaling and deep act of adopting/embracing an identity.&#13;
- The content of ethnic identity functions as a **filter** through which personal and collective goals are defined and sorted.&#13;
&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
# Managing ethnic diversity&#13;
## What is a nation?&#13;
### Defition: &#13;
_Anderson (Imagined Communities, p.6):_ An imagined political community-and imagined as both inherently limited and sovereign. &#13;
### What composes this definition?&#13;
- **Imagined**&#13;
&gt; Even in the smallest of all nations, a member will **never** know, meet, or event hear about most other members. However, the shared nation 'exists' in the consciousness of its members.&#13;
- **Limited**&#13;
&gt; People imagined nations as **bounded**: in our minds, the world population is divided to distinct nations. Perceived criteria for national membership. There are Rules for how to join 'our' nation.&#13;
- **Sovereign**&#13;
&gt; The nation is perceived by its members and outsiders who recognize its existence as sovereign or at least entitled to sovereignty. That makes the nation a **political community**: nations should **run their own business based on shared goals**.&#13;
- **Community**&#13;
&gt; The nation as an extended family or fraternity: a group whose members **share an equality at a profound level**. A community of feelings, solidarity, loyalty, and sometimes sacrifice (of people who are mostly **anonymous** to each other and also **unequal** in many respects).&#13;
&#13;
## How are (some) of the components may be related to ethnicity and interethnic relations?&#13;
- Nationhood (_sovereign_) and Nation-ness (_internal unity and cohesion_)&#13;
- A community of feelings and shared fate via the cultural stuff&#13;
- Ethnic mythology and symbols in the service of nationalism&#13;
- Myths of origin and antiquity&#13;
- A scared land via 'poetic spaces' _(e.g., archeological sites, battle fields, monuments, national map)._&#13;
- Golden age, national heroes. &#13;
- The collective past as a moral yardstick for evaluating the present and blueprint for the future via collective goals _(i.e., national revival)._&#13;
&#13;
## What is nation-state?&#13;
- A **territorially bounded sovereign** polity-ie., a state - that is **ruled in the name of a community** of citizens who **identify themselves as a nation**.&#13;
- A fusion of two principles: **state** sovereignty and **national** sovereignty.&#13;
- Nation-state institutions nurture **national sentiments**.&#13;
&gt; For members of the nation, 'their' state (which they usually see as their homeland) is the object of love, commitment or yearning.&#13;
&#13;
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]&#13;
&gt; This definition highlights that **the authority of governments** of nation-state is based on the **claim-made inwards** (i.e., the people) and **outwards** (i.e., the international community)-that the government rules in the name of a nation.&#13;
&#13;
## Solutions to the problem of incongruence of cultural and political boundaries&#13;
### Reducing / eliminating diversity：&#13;
- Oppression (by authoritarian regimes)&#13;
- Ethnic cleansing&#13;
﻿- Assimilation policies through centralized education and cultural institutions&#13;
### Managing diversity: &#13;
- Political arrangements that contain ethnic diversity and reduce conflict&#13;
&#13;
## Typology of Democracies&#13;
- Republican liberal&#13;
- Individual liberal&#13;
- Consociational&#13;
- Multicultural&#13;
- ﻿﻿Ethnic democracy&#13;
&#13;
## Some of the challenges to inclusionary management of diversity&#13;
- **Large migrations** &#13;
&gt; less assimilation + postnational incorporation (_Soysal_); resistance by host societies&#13;
- **Indigenous Movements** &#13;
&gt; request greater respect and protection for their culture and rights&#13;
- The rise of **neo-nationalism** &#13;
&gt; resulting in exclusion of multiculturalism, and even triggering discrimination and hostility towards specific ethnic or cultural groups&#13;
- Empowerment of **populist-authoritarian leaders**&#13;
&gt; tend to emphasize nationalism and xenophobia, and hold a hostile attitude towards ethnic minorities and immigrants&#13;
&#13;
## What is 'postliberal' politics / citizenship?&#13;
- Demanding **recognition** in cultural uniqueness of ethnic minority _(resistance to complete assimilation)_.&#13;
- Claiming **collective rights** for ethnic groups _(in addition to equal/just distribution of resources)_.&#13;
- Demanding **autonomy** within the state for ethnic groups in their traditional territories.&#13;
- Demanding maintenance and extension of **civil rights**.&#13;
&gt; [!NOTE]&#13;
&gt; Citizenship allows **contradictions** between autonomy and civil rights _(e.g., patriarchal norms)_&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
# Ethic stratification and inequality&#13;
## What is a **Social Stratification**?&#13;
- **Institutionalized** inequality (including legitimizing ideology)&#13;
- Inequality between **social categories**&#13;
- Inequality in access to different types of **resources** _(e.g., economic, political, legal, health, etc.)_&#13;
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]&#13;
&gt;Ethnic stratification: A state of at least **partial alignment** of ethnic division and social stratification.&#13;
&#13;
## How does status translate into economic advantages?&#13;
- Ethnic division of **labor** (monopoly over certain occupations)&#13;
- **Endogamy** (marriage as an economic exchange)&#13;
- **Stereotypes** (affect the judgment of employment, landlords, policemen, judges, etc.)&#13;
- **Ideology** may justify alignment of status and class&#13;
&#13;
## Ethnic stratification via **Political Arrangements**&#13;
- Ethnic stratification in **colonial and postcolonial** states&#13;
- **Global stratification** (_citizenship as a resource_)&#13;
&gt; There is an unequal distribution of opportunities, privileges, and resources among individuals and groups in different countries or regions. &#13;
&#13;
&gt; [!NOTE]&#13;
&gt; In this context, citizenship is seen as a valuable resource that **grants individuals specific rights, protections, and benefits** based on their country of origin or nationality.&#13;
&#13;
- **Group discrimination** by state institutions&#13;
- Differential access to certain **jobs**&#13;
- Mechanisms of inclusion/exclusion of **immigrants** based on their ethnicities&#13;
&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
# Assimilation/Integration/Segregation/Incorporation of Immigrant Ethnic minorities&#13;
## _Portes and Zhou_: Three types of **Acculturation Approach**:&#13;
- **Adoption** of the dominant culture and assimilation in the **middle-class**.&#13;
- **Adoption** of a counter-culture and assimilation in **lower classes**.&#13;
- Social and economic **mobility** through maintenance of an ethnic group's culture, values, and solidarity.&#13;
&#13;
## The Impact of the Context in the Receiving Country and Society&#13;
- Government policy: receptive, indifferent, or hostile&#13;
- Societal reception: Prejudiced or nonprejudiced&#13;
- Co-ethnic community: Weak or strong&#13;
&#13;
## What drives certain groups to 'choose' differentiation/assimilation?&#13;
- Skin color&#13;
- Place of residence&#13;
- Economic shifts&#13;
- Capacity to utilize them though different types of capital&#13;
&#13;
## The long-term effects of the 'context'&#13;
- **Government's assistance** to immigrants improves their children's (and their children's) mobility chances.&#13;
- Sometime **negative stereotypes** persist for generations.&#13;
- Immigrant's decision to join strong ethnic community may affect the **mobility of their offspring**.&#13;
&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
# Ethnic Violence&#13;
## Types of ethnic violence&#13;
-  Ethnic riot &#13;
- Lynch  &#13;
- Pogrom &#13;
- Ethnocide _(of culture)_&#13;
- Genocide (of people)&#13;
- Inter-state wars may include an ethnic component&#13;
- Civil wars&#13;
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]&#13;
&gt; Some ethnic conflicts include **more than one** type of violence.&#13;
&#13;
## Previous reasons for collective violence：&#13;
- Violence is **natural**; a human tendency that had developed through evolution.&#13;
- **Socialization** to violence&#13;
&gt; (a) arguments about **failed socialization**; (b) arguments about socialization to **non-normative behavior**.&#13;
- **Psychoanalytical** argument&#13;
&gt; e.g., (a) violence as **externalization of interna tensions**; (b) violence as projection of suppressed traumatic social relationships (for instance, _child-parents or child-teacher_).&#13;
- **Crowd** psychology&#13;
&gt; people become violent during collective action that causes **de-individuation and extasy**&#13;
&#13;
&gt; [!NOTE]&#13;
&gt; Classic arguments are partial explanation that point to possible roots of **people’s motivation** to participate in ethnic violence, but they **cannot explain instances** of ethnic violence.&#13;
&#13;
## _Ted Robert Gurr_: Reasons for ethnic violence&#13;
- The basis of violence is frustration (frustration-aggression theory).&#13;
- Frustration stems from relative deprivation (not necessarily economic).&#13;
- An ethnic group’s leadership utilizes feelings of frustration and anger to mobilize them for protest and violence. Sometimes this is done as a cold-minded strategy.&#13;
&#13;
## Characteristics of Ethnic Riot&#13;
- Brutal&#13;
- Highly passionate, but with clear patterns &#13;
&gt; e.g., target selection, common order: trigger event, rumors spread, escalation, (expansion to other places), decline.&#13;
- Violence as meaning for **participants**&#13;
- Violence has **general and immediate causes** &#13;
&gt; distal/proximate causes&#13;
&gt; Violence reflects ethnic/racial **cleavages**, but it is not a necessary outcome of the cleavages&#13;
- A process with internal dynamic&#13;
- **Trigger** events often have special **symbolic meanings**&#13;
- **Leaders** may provoke feelings of frustration, rage, hatred, and fear&#13;
&gt; including by employing elements of **collective memory**&#13;
- **Rumors** are a key mechanism of mass mobilization for active or passive support.&#13;
- **Aggressive reaction** by the rival validate negative feelings and sense of righteousness, thus propagate violence&#13;
- Violence converts negative feelings to **positive feelings**&#13;
&gt; solidarity, pride, hope, even euphoria _(Tambiah: Jubilant Destruction”)_&#13;
&#13;
## _Wimmer_: The Political Context of Violent Ethnic Conflicts&#13;
- Statistical association between ethnic violence and **political competition and exclusion**&#13;
&gt; – Ethnic uprising is more common in **ethnocracies**.&#13;
&gt; – Ethnic violence (especially coup attempts) is more common when ruling is divided between the **elites** of several ethnic groups.&#13;
&gt; – Ethnic uprising and coup attempts are more common in countries where an **ethnic minority has a history of controlling** part or the entire territory. &#13;
- Ethnic violence during the **collapse** of a polity &#13;
&gt; e.g., the Soviet Union, Yugoslavia. Mechanisms: political opportunity, contagion, security dilemma.&#13;
- Violence during or after **elections** &#13;
&gt; e.g., Kenya 2007-8 following rumors that the elections were stolen from the Kikuyu.&#13;
- Cities with **intense political competition** experience more ethnic violence&#13;
&#13;
## How people choose attitudes towards violence?&#13;
- **Rational choice**: Expected benefits/risks&#13;
&gt; Mechanisms: Social control, policing&#13;
&#13;
&gt; [!NOTE]&#13;
&gt; It is possible that rational choice is more typical of specific phases of conflicts (e.g., after escalation or when it gets clearer who is going to win)&#13;
&#13;
- **Symbolic politics**: Participation in violence is emotional and sentimental (especially hatred and rage toward the enemy).&#13;
&gt; Mechanisms: &#13;
&gt; - People’s tendency to protect their group from symbolic threats or existential threats&#13;
&gt; - Elite’s manipulative use of ethnic myths and symbols to provoke hatred, rage, and fear of the enemy + internal solidarity and excitement &#13;
&gt; - Symbolic politics flattens identities, creates “collective mind”: identity dichotomy (us/them), stereotypical thinking (good/evil) &#13;
&gt; - Affective reactions: positive feelings about the home group and negative feelings about the enemy&#13;
&gt; - A spiral of revenge and escalation &#13;
- **Institutionalized violence**: Routinization and ritualization of violence&#13;
&gt; Circumstances and Mechanisms: &#13;
&gt; - Non-violent ethnic protests deteriorates to violence&#13;
&gt; - Actors that keep the ethnic conflicts “burning” (some of them provoke violence during crises : politicians, religious leaders, mural painters, gangs, local media&#13;
&gt; - Many ordinary people have experience, or at least memories from past episodes of violence: they “know” what their role is likely to be; they remember the solidarity and elation they felt; they may wait for an opportunity for revenge&#13;
&gt; - Therefore, the violence process looks like a ritual with clear roles and a predicted pattern of development&#13;
&gt; - In some cities, violence is expected, almost trivial&#13;
&#13;
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]&#13;
&gt; The three attitudes are **not mutually exclusive** and may appear as one or multiple simultaneously。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://Yuezi-1223.github.io/yuezi.github.io/post/Study%20Note%20-%20Ethnic%20Divisions%20and%20Segregation%2C%20Harvard%202023.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 13:31:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>